enjoyshell.de 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy

www.radio.net

With this Privacy Policy, we would like to inform you about the nature, scope and purpose of the collection and processing of your personal data when using the “www.radio.net” website (hereinafter also referred to as the “ **Website** ”) operated by radio.de GmbH, Mühlenkamp 59, 22303 Hamburg, Germany (hereinafter also referred to as “ **radio.de** ”, “ **we** ” and “ **us** ”). The protection of your personal data is an important matter to radio.de when collecting and processing such data when you visit our Website. 

The controller responsible for the collection and processing of your personal data in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) (hereinafter also referred to as “ **GDPR** ”) is:

radio.de GmbH   
Mühlenkamp 59   
22303 Hamburg   
Germany 

Email: datenschutz@radio.de 

If you have any queries regarding the collection, processing and storage of personal data when using our Website, please contact our data protection officer: 

radio.de GmbH   
Data protection officer 

Mühlenkamp 59   
22303 Hamburg 

Email: dpo@radio.de 

This Privacy Policy relates to the collection and processing of personal data as part of your use of the Website operated by radio.de. Personal data refer to the individual details of the personal or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable natural person. Different data will be collected and processed depending on the extent to which you use the Website operated by us. 

## Personal data provided by the user

We collect, process and store your personal data when you access our Website. In order to enable effective use of the Website, radio.de collects data about your use of our Website in the form of so-cal ed “website log files” (hereinafter also referred to as “ **Log** **Files** ”). Each attempt to access our Website is therefore logged. The Log Files generated from this process contain the following data: 

\- Your IP address;   
Data protection officer \- Time, type and number of station requests;  
\- Your browser type and other similar information, where applicable.  

The collection and processing of information stored in the Log Files wil only be used for anonymised analysis for statistical purposes, i.e. to analyse your use of our Website and ensure continuous improvement of our services. Such data are not attributable to you as an identified person. This data will not be merged with other data sources. In order to be able to make full use of the content provided on our Website, including in particular audio services, you may create a user profile with us. This gives you the opportunity to create a favourites list of stations and songs that you can retrieve in your user profile. This allows you to access your favourite stations quickly. We can also recommend other stations to you in accordance with your favourites list. You can amend or delete your personal data or favourites lists stated in your user profile at any time. When you create a user profile, we wil collect and process the following personal data as the minimum information required: 

\- Your email address;  
\- Your user name;  
\- Your password.  

Once you have created a user profile, you wil have the option to add additional personal data to your profile on a voluntary basis. 

\- Your name;   
\- Your place of residence;  
\- Your gender;  
\- Your profile picture.  

For certain functions on our Website, it is necessary to collect location data regarding specific use of the Website in order to be able to offer you functions and services on the Website tailored to your location (such as to choose local stations, etc.). Our app therefore uses your IP address in order to determine your rough location. No conclusions can be drawn at any point about your specific location. radio.de will only use the collected location data in order to provide its services. In order to provide certain functions of the Website, radio.de must therefore process your IP address in order to be able to offer you these functions when you use the Website. Your location will only be sent to us if, when using the website, you make use of the various functions that radio.de is able to offer you once we know your location. This so-cal ed “geolocalisation”, i.e. the assignment of the opening of the Website to the location it is opened, is therefore performed using the IP address as the basis. This data wil not be merged with other data sources. 

When you use the content offered on our Website, including in particular audio services, we wil collect and process the following personal data: \- Your user profile, if created, consisting of the minimum information required and any potential additional data; 

\- Log Files;   
\- Your location.   

The legal basis for collecting and processing the data provided by you as specified above is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

As an alternative to creating your own user profile, we also offer you the opportunity to log in to our service using the “Log in with Facebook” or “Log in with Google+” buttons. This means there is no need to create an additional user profile; instead, your user profile is created using your Facebook account or your Google+ account. 

In order to log in using the “Log in with Facebook” button, you wil be directed to the Facebook website, a service provided by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA (“Facebook”), where you can log in with your user data. By doing so, this will establish a link between your Facebook profile and our Website. This link ensures that we receive the basic user data saved by Facebook and approved by you for third party services, i.e. the data which are publicly visible on your profile along with your email address. We wil only process and save your name, email address, gender and, where applicable, your profile picture from this data, provided you have given your consent for this to happen in Facebook’s settings. This information is essential for radio.de in order to be able to identity you when using your user profile. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Facebook’s privacy notices: http://www.facebook.com/policy.php. 

In order to log in using the “Log in with Google+” button, you wil be directed to the Google+ website, a service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”), where you can log in with your user data. By doing so, this wil establish a link between your Google+ profile and our Website. This link ensures that we receive the basic user data saved by Google+ and approved by you for third party services, i.e. the data which are publicly visible on your profile along with your email address and your name. We wil only process and save your name, email address, gender and your profile picture from this data, provided you have given your consent for this to happen in Google+’ settings. This information is essential for radio.de in order to be able to identity you when using your user profile. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy notices at https://policies.google.com/privacy? hl=de. 

The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

You also have the option to register for our newsletter in order to receive up-to-date and interesting radio and audio-related information. We wil collect, process and save your email address as part of the registration process for our newsletter. We will only collect, process and save your email address to the extent required in order to send the newsletter and ensure the security of our systems. If you register for our newsletter, we will ask for your consent to collect, process and save your email address. You may revoke your consent at any time by contacting us using the email address stated above, or by opting out of the newsletter via the special link provided in the respective newsletter email. 

The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

If you require assistance with regard to using our Website and the content provided on it, you can contact us directly by clicking on the “Submit Query” button. By doing so, we wil collect, process and save your email address. We wil only collect, process and save your email address to the extent required in order to process your query and ensure the security of our systems. 

The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

## Processing of personal data by third parties

radio.de works in partnership with the following external web host in order to process your data in a secure and efficient manner. 

The web host is mpex GmbH, Werner-Voß-Damm 62, 12101 Berlin, Germany. mpex GmbH is certified to “ISO/IEC 27001” and “Trust in Cloud Infrastructure”. “ISO 27001” is an international y recognised standard for information security which takes into account data security, data protection and reliability. mpex GmbH’s Privacy Policy can be found at https://www.mpex.de/impressum.html#datenschutz. 

Any personal data collected as part of your use of our Website wil only be processed by radio.de and third parties stated in this Privacy Policy. Furthermore, radio.de wil not disclose personal data to any third parties. Personal data wil only be disclosed to third parties in exceptional cases where radio.de is obliged to disclose the collected data on the basis of an official or judicial order. 

## Purpose of the collection, processing and storage of your personal data

We will initially only collect, process and save your personal data to the extent required from a technical perspective in order to provide our Website. By collecting, processing and storing your personal data, we can therefore ensure the security of radio.de, and by doing so we can also ensure that you are able to access our content efficiently and conveniently. In order to be able to adapt our Website in line with the constantly changing technical environment and security framework, we wil also use your personal data to ensure the continuous improvement of our Website. 

## Duration of storage and erasure of personal data

Personal data which are collected and processed by us as part of the registration process for our services, i.e. when creating a user profile, wil be stored for as long as is necessary in order to provide our services; this wil typically be for as long as you have a user profile registered with radio.de. Personal data stored in your user profile wil be erased if you delete your user profile or if such storage is no longer permissible for other reasons. 

Your data stored in Log Files wil be erased if such data are no longer required to fulfil the purpose related to the storage. 

Your personal data wil also be erased after you have revoked your consent for such storage, where applicable. 

Such erasure does not include data, the rectification, blocking or erasure of which run contrary to legal, statutory or contractual retention periods, as wel as data required for the establishment, content-related creation or amendment of a contractual relationship with us, or data which must be stored for bil ing purposes. 

## Cookies

radio.de uses so-called cookies. Cookies are small text files which are stored by your browser on your computer. As a result, the collection of cookies makes it easier for you to use our services and al ows us to better understand your user behaviour and be able to offer you suitable content and tailored services in line with your requirements. 

radio.de uses so-called technically necessary cookies on the one hand. Some elements of radio.de require the browser you are using to be identified even after switching pages. The purpose of using technical y necessary cookies is to make our Website easier for users like you to use. Some functions of our Website cannot be offered without the use of cookies. These functions require the browser to be recognised again after switching pages. The data stored by the cookies include, among others, your choice of stations. As part of the various services offered, these cookies allow us to receive your personal settings over a longer period of time. radio.de also uses cookies which enable analysis of users’ browsing habits. This relates in particular to the utilisation of different functions on our Website and the frequency pages are accessed. These cookies are used for the purpose of continuously improving the quality of content provided by radio.de and aligning this content to the user behaviour. The cookies tell us how the Website is used, enabling us to constantly optimise our offering. The data collected in this way are pseudonymised by technological means. Therefore, assignment of the data to the requesting user is no longer possible. The data are not stored together with users’ other personal data. The legal basis for collecting and processing the data collected and processed using the cookies is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Al cookies are stored on your computer and then sent from your browser to radio.de. You, as the user, therefore have ful control over the use of cookies. You can disable or restrict the transmission of cookies by adjusting the settings in your web browser. Cookies which have already been saved can be deleted at any time. This may also be done automatically. However, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so it is also possible that certain content on the Website cannot be used or cannot be used in full. 

## Google Analytics

radio.de uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, (“Google”). Google Analytics also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of your use of our Website. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. If IP anonymisation is activated by radio.de, however, your IP address wil first be truncated by Google within the member states of the European Union or other States party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Google wil use this information on behalf of radio.de to analyse your use of the Website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide radio.de with other services relating to the Website and internet use. The IP address sent by your browser as part of Google Analytics wil not be linked to any other data held by Google. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy policy at https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data (including your IP address) generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Google as wel as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the fol owing link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de. 

## Google Optimize

radio.de uses Google Optimize, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, (“Google”). Google Optimize analyses the use of different versions of our Website and helps us to personalise its user friendliness in line with our users’ behaviour on the Website. Google Optimize is a tool integrated into Google Analytics. Google Optimize also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of your use of our Website. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. If IP anonymisation is activated by radio.de, however, your IP address will first be truncated by Google within the member states of the European Union or other States party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Google will use this information on behalf of radio.de to analyse your use of the Website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide radio.de with other services relating to the Website and internet use. The IP address sent by your browser as part of Google Optimize wil not be linked to any other data held by Google. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy policy at https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data (including your IP address) generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Google as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and instal ing the browser plugin available at the fol owing link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de. 

## New Relic

radio.de uses NewRelic, a web analytics service provided by New Relic Inc., 188 Spear Street, Suite 1200, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA, (“New Relic”). New Relic also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer and enable a statistical analysis of the Website's speed, in order to determine whether the Website can be accessed and how quickly the respective Website page is displayed when accessed. The Website can therefore be designed in a manner to cater for demand. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. When you access our Website, your browser wil establish a direct link to New Relic's servers. In doing so, New Relic receives information stating that you have accessed the corresponding page on our Website. New Relic wil store the IP address. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by New Relic and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in New Relic's privacy notices: https://newrelic.com/terms-and-conditions/privacy. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Website. 

## InfoOnline/ÖWA

radio.de uses the Scaleable Centralised Measuring System [Skalierbares Zentrales Messverfahren (SZM)] of INFOnline GmbH, Brühler Str. 9, D-53119 Bonn (“InfoOnline” and “SZM”) to determine statistical values regarding the use of the Website. Measurement values are collected in anonymous format. As an alternative way to recognise devices, the SZM range measurement uses either a cookie or a signature generated from various information transferred automatical y from your device. IP addresses are not stored in the process, and only processed in anonymised form. The aim of the audience measurement is to statistical y determine the usage intensity and the number of users on a Website. Individual users wil not be identified at any point. Your identity wil always remain protected. You will not receive any ads via the system. By using this measuring system, our Website also participates in the audience measurement performed by Arbeitsgemeinschaft Online-Forschung e.V. (“AGOF”) [Working Group for Online Media Research] as wel as the al iances between Informationsgemeinschaft zur Feststellung der Verbreitung von Werbeträgern e. V. (“IVW“) [German Audit Bureau of Circulation] and Arbeitsgemeinschaft Media-Analyse e.V. (“agma”) [Media Analysis Council]. AGOF, IVW and agma issue reports on a regular basis in studies about the usage statistics of participating services. Our Website also uses the Scaleable Centralised Measuring System [Skalierbares Zentrales Messverfahren (SZM)], an analysis system provided by the Österreichische Webanalyse association [Austrian Web Analysis association], Köl nerhofgasse 2/8, 1010 Vienna, Austria, (“ÖWA”). Measurement values are collected in anonymous format. As an alternative way to recognise devices, the SZM range measurement uses either a cookie or a signature generated from various information transferred automatical y from your device. IP addresses are not stored in the process, and only in anonymised form. The aim of the audience measurement is to statistical y determine the usage intensity and the number of users on a Website. Individual users wil not be identified at any point. Your identity wil always remain protected. You will not receive any ads via the system. The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. You can find out more information about the SZM system at https://www.infonline.de/datenschutz or http://www.oewa.at/datenschutz-erklaerung. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of our Website by InfoOnline and ÖWA as well as the processing of this data by InfoOnline and ÖWA by using the opt out feature for InfoOnline at https://optout.ioam.de, and the opt out feature for ÖWA at https://optout-at.iocnt.net/optout.php. 

## Zendesk

radio.de uses Zendesk, a customer service platform provided by Zendesk Inc., 1019 Market Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Zendesk”). Zendesk is a ticket system used to process customer queries. In order to use Zendesk, the necessary data such as your email >address (as described above in this Privacy Policy) are collected via our Website in order to be able to process your support ticket. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. When processing service queries, it may be necessary to collect additional data (such as your name and address). radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Zendesk and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Zendesk's privacy notices: https://www.zendesk.de/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/. 

radio.de uses different advertising marketers and other external service providers to display on-demand online ads. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in optimising our services and marketing our products. 

## Urban Media

radio.de has commissioned Urban Media GmbH, Askanischer Platz 3, 10963 Berlin, Germany (“Urban Media”) with regard to the digital marketing of ads on our Website. Ads on our Website marketed by Urban Media are optimised by virtue of the anonymous collection and processing of your usage behaviour and aligned with predicted interests. By doing so, you as a user wil benefit by receiving ads which are better targeted to your areas of interest, as wel as by way of the fact that you will receive a less random spread of ads. By setting cookies, pseudonymised and/or anonymised data, such as data contained in IP addresses, browser information or data regarding click-based promotions for ad displays, are typical y collected and processed as part of your use of our Website. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Urban Media and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Urban Media’s privacy policy at https://www.urban-media.com/datenschutz/. 

Urban Media works in partnership with specific external advertising service providers. If cookies are set, you can prevent the instal ation of cookies using the corresponding setting in your browser software. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by the respective external service providers as wel as the processing of this data by the respective external service providers by using the opt out features shown below: 

### Outbrain

Outbrain uses technologies developed by Outbrain Inc, 39 West 13th Street, New York, NY 10011, USA. Privacy Policy: https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy%23privacy-policy Opt out: https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy%23 

### Inskin

Inskin uses technologies developed by Inskin Media Ltd., 233 High Holborn Street, London, WC1V 7DN, UK. Privacy Policy: http://www.inskinmedia.com/de/datenschutzrichtlinien.html Opt out: http://www.inskinmedia.com/de/datenschutzrichtlinien.html#Optout 

### YOC

YOC uses technologies developed by YOC AG, Greifswalder Str. 212, 10405 Berlin, Germany. Privacy Policy:https://yoc.com/de/datenschutz/ Opt out: https://t.visx.net/opt-out 

### FutureTV

FutureTV uses technologies developed by FutureTV GmbH & Co. KG, Goethestraße 19, 18055 Rostock, Germany. Privacy Policy: https://www.futuretv-group.com/privacy-for-publishers/ 

### Teads

Teads uses technologies developed by Teads SA, 5, rue de la Boucherie, L-1247 Luxembourg. Privacy Policy: https://teads.tv/privacy-policy/ Opt out: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices 

### Content Garden

Content Garden uses technologies developed by content garden technologies GmbH, Gumpendorfer Straße 132/1/8, 1060 Vienna, Austria. Privacy Policy: http://www.content-garden.com/datenschutz/ Opt out: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/at/praferenzmanagement 

### Plista

Plista uses technologies developed by plista GmbH, Torstraße 33-35, 10119 Berlin, Germany. Privacy Policy: https://www.plista.com/de/about/privacy/ Opt out: https://www.plista.com/de/about/privacy/ 

### define media

define media uses technologies developed by define media GmbH, An der Raumfabrik 31a, D-76227 Karlsruhe, Germany. Privacy Policy: http://www.definemedia.de/datenschutz/ Opt out: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices 

### Adyoulike

Adyoulike uses technologies developed by Adyoulike SAS, 37 rue Boissière, 75116 Paris, France. Privacy Policy: https://www.adyoulike.com/privacy_policy.php Opt out: https://www.adyoulike.com/privacy_policy.php 

### AppNexus

AppNexus uses technologies developed by AppNexus Inc., 8 West 23rd Street, 4th Floor, New York, NY 10010, USA. Privacy Policy: https://www.appnexus.com/platform-privacy-policy Opt out: https://www.appnexus.com/platform-privacy-policy#choices 

### OpenX

OpenX uses technologies developed by OpenX Technologies, Inc., 888 East Walnut Street 2nd Floor, Pasadena, CA 91101, USA. Privacy Policy: https://www.open-xchange.com/privacy/ Opt out: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/ 

### Index Exchange

Index Exchange uses technologies developed by Index Exchange Inc., 74 Wingold Avenue, Toronto, ON M6B 1P5, Canada. Privacy Policy: http://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/ Opt out: http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/ 

### Emetriq

Emetriq uses technologies developed by emetriq GmbH, Vorsetzen 35, 20459 Hamburg, Germany. Privacy Policy: https://www.emetriq.com/datenschutz/ Opt out: https://www.emetriq.com/opt-out/ 

### Goldbach Audience

Radio.de has also commissioned Goldbach Audience Austria GmbH, Laimgrubengasse 14, 1060 Vienna, Austria (“Goldbach Audience”) with regard to the digital marketing of ads on our Website. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Goldbach Audience and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Goldbach Audience’s privacy policy at http://www.goldbachaustria.at/de- at/datenschutz. 

### Google DFP

radio.de uses Google DFP for Smal Business, an ad display service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google DFP”). Google DFP makes use of technologies to display ads which are of relevance to you. Your browser wil be assigned a pseudonymous identification number (ID) via a cookie, which is used to check which ads have been displayed in your browser and which ads were viewed. The use of DoubleClick cookies only al ows Google and its partner websites as wel as other third parties on whose behalf Google is acting to display ads based on previous visits to our Website or other websites on the Internet. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information collected by cookies is usual y sent to a Google server in the USA for evaluation purposes and stored there. Google wil only transmit data to third parties on the basis of statutory provisions or in the event of commissioned data processing between Google and its partners, such as Display Networks etc.. Under no circumstances wil Google associate your data with any other data collected by Google. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy notices at https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. You can prevent the instal ation of cookies using the corresponding setting in your browser software. However, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of the Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookies and related to your use of the Website by Google as wel as the processing of this data by Google by using the opt out feature at https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous? hl=en-GB&sig=ACi0TCgVUscuN_tZBfDB- G61F86nfP2kJQwBIVeLpcsavRDFandA8o5ATDW_XIoP949CmidQVO70. 

### Google DoubleClick Ad Exchange

radio.de uses Google DoubleClick Ad Exchange, a real-time marketplace for purchasing and selling digital ads provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google AdX”). In order to activate ads on our Website (text ads, banners etc.), >your browser may possibly store a cookie sent by Google AdX or a third party on whose behalf Google is acting. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information stored in the cookie may be collected, processed and saved by Google AdX or third parties. In addition, Google AdX also makes use of so-cal ed “Web Beacons” (smal invisible graphics), the use of which enables the collecting, processing and storage of basic actions, such as visitor traffic to a given website. The information generated by the cookie and/or Web Beacon about your use of this Website wil be transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google uses the information obtained in this manner to provide an analysis of your usage behaviour. If necessary, Google wil also transmit this data to third parties, provided this is required by law or the third party is processing the data at the request of Google. Google wil not link your IP address to other data stored by Google. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy notices at https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. You may prevent cookies and Web Beacons being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also restrict collection of the data (including your IP address) generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Google as wel as the processing of this data by Google by amending the display settings for ads. You can find out more information about this feature at https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/technologies/ads/. 

### Google Adwords

radio.de uses Google Adwords, an analytics service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google Adwords”). radio.de uses the Google Adwords service in order to publicise our Website on external websites with the aid of advertising means (so-cal ed Google Adwords). radio.de is then able to determine how successful the individual advertising measures are in relation to the data from the advertising campaigns. A cookie (“conversion cookie”) is placed on your device by Google Adwords for this purpose if you have reached our Website via a Google Ad. These cookies lose their effectiveness after 30 days and cannot be used for personal identification. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. If you visit certain pages on our Website or perform certain actions within the Website (such as starting a station, etc.) and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google will be able to tell that you were directed to our Website’s page via the ad and are using the Website. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Therefore, cookies cannot be tracked via AdWords customer websites. Information >obtained with the aid of the “conversion cookie” is used to generate conversion statistics. radio.de wil be informed about the total number of users who have clicked on an ad and were directed to a page with a conversion tracking tag, along with information about activities undertaken on the Website. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy policy at https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also restrict collection of the data (including your IP address) generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Google as wel as the processing of this data by Google by amending the display settings for ads. You can find out more information about this feature at https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/technologies/ads/. 

### Google Adsense

radio.de uses Google Adsense, an ad display service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google Adsense”). In order to activate ads on our Website (text ads, banners etc.), your browser will store a cookie sent by Google Adsense or a third party on whose behalf Google is acting. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information stored in the cookie may be collected, processed and stored by Google Adsense or third parties as wel . In addition, Google Adsense also makes use of so-called “Web Beacons” (smal invisible graphics), the use of which enables the recording, collection and evaluation of basic actions, such as visitor traffic to the Website. The information generated by the cookie and/or Web Beacon about your use of this Website wil be transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google uses the information obtained in this manner to provide an analysis of your usage behaviour with regard to AdSense ads. If necessary, Google wil also transmit this data to third parties, provided this is required by law or the third party is processing the data at the request of Google. Google wil not link your IP address to other data stored by Google. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy notices at https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. You may prevent cookies and Web Beacons being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if >you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also restrict collection of the data (including your IP address) generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Google as wel as the processing of this data by Google by amending the display settings for ads. You can find out more information about this feature at https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/technologies/ads/. 

### AdDefend

In order to display ads, radio.de uses AdDefend, a service provided by AdDefend GmbH, Borselstrasse 3, 22765 Hamburg, Germany (“AdDefend”). AdDefend also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer and allow you to determine whether a website has already been visited. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to an AdDefend server and stored there. AdDefend will use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by AdDefend and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in AdDefend's privacy policy at https://www.ad-defend.com/de/datenschutzerklarung/. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by AdDefend as wel as the processing of this data by AdDefend by using the opt out feature at https://www.addefend.com/de/opt-out/. 

### Bing Ads

In order to display ads, radio.de uses Bing Ads, a service provided by Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA (“Bing Ads”). A cookie (“conversion cookie”) is placed on your device by Bing Ads for this purpose if you have reached our Website via a Microsoft Bing Ad. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. If you visit certain pages on our Website or perform certain actions within the Website (such as starting a station, etc.) and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Bing Ads will be able to tell that you were directed to our Website’s page via the ad and are using the Website. Information obtained with the aid of the “conversion cookie” is used to generate conversion statistics. radio.de wil be informed about the total number of users who have clicked on an ad and were directed to a page with a conversion tracking tag, along with information about activities undertaken on the Website. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Microsoft and your rights and configuration options >concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Microsoft's privacy policy at https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Microsoft as well as the processing of this data by Microsoft by using the opt out feature at http://choice.microsoft.com/de-DE/opt-out. 

### Facebook Pixel

In order to display ads, radio.de uses a visitor behaviour pixel provided by Facebook, a service operated by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA (“Facebook”) . By using the Facebook pixel, it is possible to track that you were directed to our Website by clicking on a Facebook ad display. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. In doing so, the effectiveness of Facebook ad displays can be evaluated for statistical and market research purposes and future advertising measures can also be optimised. radio.de is unable to draw conclusions about the identity of users from the data collected. The data are saved and processed by Facebook so that a link to the respective user profile is possible and Facebook can use the data for its own advertising purposes, in accordance with the Facebook data use policy. In doing so, Facebook is able to activate ad displays on Facebook's own pages as wel as on pages outside of Facebook. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Facebook's privacy policy at http://www.facebook.com/policy.php. You can edit the settings for on- demand online ads in the Ad Settings area at https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/? entry_prod-uct=ad_settings_screen. You must be logged in to Facebook to do this. If you do not have a Facebook account, you can disable Facebook’s on-demand ads by using the opt out feature at http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/. 

### Freewheel

In order to include video campaigns, radio.de uses Freewheel, a service provided by Comcast International France SAS, 115-123 Avenue Charles de Gaul e, 92200 Neuil y-Sur- Seine, France (“Freewheel”). Freewheel also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a Freewheel server and stored there. Freewheel wil use this information on behalf of radio.de >in order to feature video campaigns on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Freewheel and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Freewheel's privacy policy at http://freewheel.tv/privacy-policy-de/. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Freewheel as well as the processing of this data by Freewheel by using the opt out feature at http://freewheel.tv/optout-html/. 

### Smartclip 

In order to display ads, radio.de uses Smartclip, a service provided by Smartclip Holding AG, Kleiner Burstah 12, Nikolaikontor, 20457 Hamburg, Germany (“Smartclip”). Smartclip also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a Smartclip server and stored there. Smartclip will use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Smartclip and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Smartclip's privacy policy at http://privacy-portal.smartclip.net. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Smartclip as wel as the processing of this data by Smartclip by using the opt out feature at http://privacy- portal.smartclip.net/de/opt-out. 

### Smartstream 

In order to display ads, radio.de uses Smartstream, a service provided by Smartstream.TV GmbH, Dachauer Str. 15c, 80335 Munich, Germany (“Smartstream”). Smartstream also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a Smartstream server and stored there. Smartstream wil use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Smartstream and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Smartstream's privacy policy at https://smartstream.tv/de/datenschutz. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Smartstream as wel as the processing of this data by Smartstream by using the opt out feature at https://www.smartstream.tv/en/cookie-opt-out. 

### Smaato

In order to display ads, radio.de uses Smaato, a service provided by Smaato Inc., 240 Stockton Street, 10th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94108, USA (“Smaato”). Smaato also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a Smaato server and stored there. Smaato will use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Smaato and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Smaato's privacy policy at https://www.smaato.com/privacy/. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Smaato as well as the processing of this data by Smaato by using the opt out feature at https://www.youronlinechoices.eu. 

### SpotX

In order to display ads, radio.de uses SpotX, a service provided by SpotX Inc., 8181 Arista Place, Broomfield, CO 80021, USA (“SpotX”). SpotX also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a SpotX server and stored there. SpotX wil use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by SpotX and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in SpotX's privacy policy at https://www.spotx.tv/privacy-policy/. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by SpotX as wel as the processing of this data by SpotX by using the opt out feature at https://www.spotx.tv/privacy-policy/. 

### Yieldlove 

In order to display ads, radio.de uses Yieldlove, a service provided by Yieldlove GmbH, Kehrwieder 9, 20457 Hamburg, Germany (“Yieldlove”). Yieldlove also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usual y transferred to a Yieldlove server and stored there. Yieldlove wil use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Yieldlove and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Yieldlove's privacy policy at http://yieldlove.com/cookie-policy. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by Yieldlove as well as the processing of this data by Yieldlove by using the opt out feature at http://yieldlove.com/cookie-policy. 

### YOC

In order to display ads, radio.de uses YOC, a service provided by YOC AG, Greifswalder Str. 212, 10405 Berlin, Germany, (“YOC”). YOC also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1)( f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usually transferred to a YOC server and stored there. YOC will use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by YOC and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in YOC's privacy policy at https://yoc.com/de/datenschutz/. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by YOC as wel as the processing of this data by YOC by using the opt out feature at https://t.visx.net/opt-out. 

### IndexExchange

In order to display ads, radio.de uses IndexExchange, a service provided by Index Exchange Inc., 74 Wingold Avenue, Toronto, ON M6B 1P5, Canada (“IndexExchange”). IndexExchange also uses cookies, text files that are stored on your computer. The legal basis for collecting data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this Website is usually transferred to an IndexExchange server and stored there. >IndexExchange wil use this information on behalf of radio.de in order to feature ads on our Website. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by IndexExchange and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in IndexExchange's privacy policy at http://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/. You may prevent cookies being stored on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, radio.de wishes to point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use the ful functionality of this Website. As a user, you can also prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the Website by IndexExchange as well as the processing of this data by IndexExchange by using the opt out feature at http://optout.networkadvertising.org/? c=1#!/. 

## Social plugins

The following social plugins (“Plugins”) are used on our Website: 

### Facebook

Our website uses Plugins from the social media network Facebook, operated by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA (“Facebook”). An overview of Facebook Plugins and their appearance can be found here: https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/. 

If you are logged into Facebook when accessing our Website, Facebook can immediately assign your visit to our Website to your Facebook profile. If you interact with the Plugin, the corresponding information is sent directly to Facebook’s server and stored there. The information will typical y also be published on your Facebook profile and notified to your Facebook friends and/or al Facebook members. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Facebook and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Facebook’s privacy policy: http://www.facebook.com/policy.php. 

If you do not want Facebook to assign the data collected from our Website to your Facebook profile, you have to log out of Facebook before visiting our Website. You can also ful y prevent Facebook Plugins from being downloaded with add-ons for your browser. 

The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

### Google+

Our website uses Plugins from the social media network Google+, operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, (“Google”). An overview of Google+ Plugins and their appearance can be found here: https://developers.google.com/ +/web/. 

If you are logged into Google+ when accessing our Website, Google can immediately assign your visit to our Website to your Google+ profile. If you interact with the Plugin, the corresponding information is sent directly to the Google+ server and stored there. The information wil typical y also be published on your Google+ profile and notified to your Google+ friends. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Google+ and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Google's privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy? hl=de. 

If you do not want Google to assign the data collected from our Website to your Google+ profile, you have to log out of Google+ before visiting our Website. You can also ful y prevent Google+ Plugins from being downloaded with add-ons for your browser. The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

### Twitter+

Our Website uses Plugins from the microblogging service Twitter, operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Twitter”). An overview of Twitter Plugins and their appearance can be found here: https://twitter.com/about/resources/buttons. 

If you are logged into Twitter when accessing our Website, Twitter can immediately assign your visit to our Website to your Twitter account. If you interact with the Plugin, the corresponding information is sent directly to Twitter's server and stored there. radio.de does not have any influence on the extent of any such data collection. The purpose and scope of the data collection, and the further processing and use of the data by Twitter and your rights and configuration options concerning this to protect your privacy, can be found in Twitter's privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de. 

>If you do not want Twitter to assign the data collected from our Website to your Twitter profile, you have to log out of Twitter before visiting our Website. You can also ful y prevent Twitter Plugins from being downloaded with add-ons for your browser. 

The legal basis for collecting and processing your personal data is Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

## Legal basis for processing your personal data

Your personal data will be collected, processed and stored in accordance with GDPR provisions as well as in accordance with the relevant provisions under EU law and national law. 

Where the collection, processing or storage of such data are necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party, or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR wil form the legal basis for the collection, processing and storage of your personal data. 

Where the collection, processing or storage of such data are necessary for the performance of a legal obligation under Union law or national statutory provisions which radio.de is subject to, Article 6 (1) (c) GDPR will form the legal basis for the collection, processing and storage of your personal data. 

If the collection, processing and storage of your personal data is necessary for the protection of the legitimate interests of radio.de or a third party and such interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms, Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR forms the legal basis for the collection, processing and storage of your personal data. 

In cases where none of these statutory provisions are applicable, the collection, processing and storage of your personal data wil only be undertaken subject to your separate consent. Where necessary, you can provide your explicit consent when visiting the services provided by radio.de on our Website by way of a brief separate electronic confirmation. Where radio.de obtains your separate consent for the processing of personal data, Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR forms the legal basis for the collection, processing and storage of your personal data. 

Please also note the information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy on your rights regarding the protection of your personal data. 

## Your rights regarding the protection of your personal data

You shall be entitled to the fol owing rights, to the extent of the respective provision, in accordance with GDPR provisions as wel as in accordance with the relevant provisions under EU law and national law: 

### Right of access

You can request confirmation from radio.de as to whether personal data concerning you are collected, processed and stored by radio.de. If such data are collected, processed or stored, you may request information from radio.de about the purposes to which the personal data are being collected and processed and the planned duration for which the personal data concerning you are due to be stored or, if this cannot be specified, the criteria for defining the storage period. 

Please send your written request for information to: 

radio.de GmbH  
Mühlenkamp 59  
22303 Hamburg  
Germany

Email: datenschutz@radio.de

### Right to rectification and completion

You are entitled to request that radio.de rectifies and/or completes your personal data if the collected and processed personal data are incorrect or incomplete. Right to restriction of processing You can request the processing of personal data concerning you to be restricted. 

### Right to erasure

You can request that radio.de deletes your personal data immediately. radio.de is then obliged to delete such data immediately if the personal data concerning you are no longer required to achieve the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed, or you have withdrawn your consent on the basis of which the data were collected, processed or stored. The right to erasure wil not apply if the processing of such data is necessary to fulfil a statutory obligation demanding the collection and processing of data according to Union law or Member State law which radio.de is subject to, and if the collection and processing of such data is necessary for the assertion, exercising or defence of legal claims. 

### Right to data portability

You have the right to receive personal data concerning you which you have provided to us as the controller for data collection in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You also have the right to transmit such data to another controller without hindrance from the controller to whom the personal data were provided. 

### Right to object

You have the right, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to object at any time to the collection or processing of personal data concerning you that is performed in accordance with Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR. 

### Right to withdraw declaration of consent

If you have given us your consent in collecting and processing your personal data, you have the right to withdraw your declaration of consent under data protection law at any time. Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement, if you believe that the collection and processing of personal data concerning you is unlawful. 

As part of the further development of the services provided and the implementation of new technologies, radio.de reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time. radio.de therefore requests that you keep yourself regularly informed of the Privacy Policy here. 

Last updated: August 2018
